[Music]
What happens when you die is a topic of
great intrigue for everyone but we're not
talking about something spiritual like if you go
to heaven Or if everything ends we're
referring to What do they do with our
corpse What things don't they tell you about
cremations Can a deceased woman
give birth to a baby stay until the
end because we assure you that
today's video will leave you with your mouth
open there is something that draws a lot of
attention and it is what some call the
screams of the dead many say that
watching over the deceased at home as it was
done before and still is done in many
homes these heard the deceased
scream are they inventions or something paranormal
everything usually coincides in the type of
noise they emit resembling screams or
moans of suffering This is not
pleasant at all because it makes people believe
that the deceased is reviving of
course this has an explanation
the body is a natural storage
for gases which after death
increase due to the activity of
bacteria given the large amount of gases
these seek to leave the body and one of
the most accessible ways to do so is
the trachea  generating those
noises This is the reason why
funeral homes must expel them from the
body when they aspirate the trachea and the
gases pass through the vocal cords
too Professionals can
hear what sounds like a
terrifying scream from the person
but they are only gases tic tackers the
dead person does not emit anything with his voice do not
confuse it breath which is when
the last contraction of the
diaphragm occurs as if this were not enough
corpses can also make some
movement for several hours after
dying something very disturbing for
anyone who is nearby however
these involuntary movements in the
muscles are something normal after having
died it is attributed to the period in which
the nervous system still sends
signals to the spinal cord and in turn
causes jerks and spasms some
morticians have reported that on
occasions the deceased has half sat
up on the stretcher as if
trying to sit up and have gone back to
bed for a few very
disturbing seconds a myth about the
dead is that the nails and hair
continue to grow a little more but
this is not true the
growth process stops on the day of
Death people believed it because it was the
impression given by seeing the deceased
but in reality what happens is that the
rest of the body shrinks with the
loss of moisture that
death entails along with the stoppage of
tissue production the skin begins to
contract that is to say it is not that the nail is
bigger but the skin that surrounds it
retracts and therefore we see more of
it in terms of hair such as
the beard which is an area where we
can best see the difference in size it
may be that on the day of his death a
man had a day old beard and then it
seems that it has grown a few
millimeters this is also produced by
the contraction of the erector muscles
of the hair that make them look
longer another curious fact is that some
male corpses suffer the
involuntary elevation of their most intimate part it is
one of the best known movements post morte
the heart stops and stops
pumping which causes the blood to
concentrate in the lower parts of the
body when placing the deceased standing or
lying face down this phenomenon could occur
continuing with more curiosities
one of the questions that  we were asking at the
beginning of the video is whether a
dead pregnant woman could give birth to a
baby Well as incredible as it may seem
The answer is yes and we are not referring to
a cesarean section but to being able to expel
the baby the scientific explanation is
attributed to the aforementioned gas and the
relaxation of the muscles two factors
that together cause the expulsion
of the fetus or anything else that is
inside the body this
also occurs with urine or feces
that are expelled
involuntarily after
death news that made
this topic go viral that few knew about was
the death of a South African woman who
died while she was pregnant
The death of the woman and the fetus was declared
and since they followed other types of
protocols their cavities were not sealed
and the corpse was placed in the coffin
when days later they opened the coffin
for the ceremony they discovered that
next to her was the corpse of a
newborn baby the woman had given birth
inside
involuntarily many spoke of
witchcraft but it is something with a
biological explanation death is a subject that for
some becomes an  complete
suffering thinking about it when will it happen
what will they do to me if there is one thing that is clear is
that we cannot avoid it in
most cases we will end up in the hands
of a funeral home at that moment the
body becomes the responsibility of the
mortician who will be in charge of
preparing the deceased for the
funeral first the
items that he has are removed we are not only talking about
clothes or jewelry but also other
elements such as
pacemakers once this is done the
whole body is disinfected
including all the orifices for this they
use a very strong disinfectant the
next step is to loosen the muscles
of the neck arms and legs that have
become stiff due to rigor mortis For
example if a person has died and
has been left with their hand in the shape of a fist
and has a ring that the family wants to
recover if rigor mortis has already begun
the deceased will not open their fist
easily therefore the professional must
slowly massage their
hand and arm several times until they get their
muscles to relax and can open their fist
after this continues with the
face when we die a
decomposition process occurs the
softest and most membranous tissue begins to dry out and
this causes  the eyes begin to
sink into the socket to avoid being
noticed when the deceased is watched by
their relatives, a piece of
plastic with a hemispherical surface is placed
just below the eyelids and between the
plastic and the inside of the eyelid the
mortician applies a
moisturizing cream, thus creating the appearance that
the skin on the outside is hydrated
and soft. They also apply
glue to the edge of the eyelids
so that they do not open the next step
would be to keep the mouth completely
closed the mouth of the deceased has to
be sealed to prevent the escape of
odors and the spread of bacteria. A
person can die in
very different circumstances and in many of them they
may die with their mouth open and because it
is stiff it is difficult to close it. In
some cases the mortician must
break some bones, use wires,
and some other material to join everything together, and
put the mouth back in place
to keep it closed,
glue is used. Although others choose to sew, and
in cases where the corpse loses
teeth and the mouth looks deformed, it is
filled with cotton to
shape the face. sometimes
latex prostheses or serum injections are made.
physiological in the lips if they have
become very dehydrated what is
sought at all times is that the
result is as natural and as
similar as possible to their image in
life another of the fundamental parts
to prepare a dead person is the removal
of all the blood that may be inside
your body for this, it begins by
pricking a needle into one of the
main arteries after this,
a formula
composed of formaldehyde and other
chemicals is slowly introduced with this process
all the blood is drained little by little
through a syringe that is
connected to a valve at the end
all the blood is left out and inside the
body about 2 liters of embalming liquid remain
this helps the body to
last longer without decomposing so
at the time of the funeral it will be in good
condition then continues with the
embalming of the cavities the
professional drains the gases that remain
inside as well as the liquids these
liquids are usually located in
some of the organs of the deceased such as
the stomach, bladder or lungs
to be able to remove it an incision is made
in the abdominal area and a
tool known as a trocar is inserted which
is connected to a suction pump
then the internal organs are punctured
to drain the fluid and are replaced
with embalming fluids. in addition, the
other orifices such as the anus, vagina,
ears or nose are also filled with
cotton to prevent the release of
body gases or the proliferation of
bacteria. if the deceased had been an
organ donor, the extraction would not be
performed here but in a hospital or
also at the university. if they are donated
for science they must do the
extraction as soon as possible and preserve the organ in
another type of substance. if the family
wishes to bury the rest of the body,
a filling is placed in the
abdominal structure and sew it up. They do this with
care and respect to deliver it in the
best
[Music]
conditions. following the
funeral home process, the next step is the
final preparation of the body for the
funeral. This is one of the most
important parts of how a death is prepared
since it is the image that the
family and friends of the
deceased will be able to see. for aesthetic mortuary treatments,
materials such as foundations,
corrective powders, lipsticks, gels and
many varieties of
makeup elements in general are used. The main thing is to
give expressiveness to the face in addition to
looking for an appearance of vitality. The
professional begins the  process drying
the entire body and hair Arranging it
so that it is well prepared even
affect men if necessary
then dress him with the clothes chosen
by the family and correct any
problem that is visible in the face hands or
neck be it wounds bruises. For this
the combination of makeup
with waxes and putty is used the latter is very
useful to cover injuries or cuts the
tone of the skin of the deceased is no longer the
same so with several layers of
makeup base and concealer they manage to
give it a tone similar to that of a alive in
the case of people who have died
asphyxiated the skin acquires a blue tone
so they must use dense makeup
to counteract the real color something
curious is that the deceased have
fewer wrinkles on the face and it is because when
the muscles relax the
facial wrinkles are attenuated it is not because they
inject him with botox the makeup is good
but not miraculous either finally they
place the deceased in the coffin
arranging his head neck arms and
legs in a natural position that gives
the sensation of being resting and without
pain the best known way to say
goodbye  to our deceased is
through a burial the ritual in which
the body of the loved one is
placed in a coffin that is placed
underground or in different types of
niches in cemeteries however it
is also very common for relatives to
choose cremation although we can
summarize the process as in which the
human body is reduced to ashes we
have informed ourselves through several
articles and testimonies to
tell you what is not
talked about for cremation
special large ovens are used with
temperatures of around 900 1000 grc
to achieve maximum disintegration of the
body and we say maximum since
we believed that in this process the
entire body was reduced to ashes in
the oven but from several testimonies of
thanatopractor on networks it seems that
this is not the case since at the end of the
process there are still several bones inside
and this is because to
completely dissolve they would need much more
time but how do these bones turn
into ash we take this
opportunity to tell you that we are not
professionals in this subject all the
information in the video is the result of
searches on funeral websites
thanatopraxy courses and public testimonies of
thanatopractor as we were telling you
when the cremation process is carried out
not everything is reduced to
ashes the body is placed in the
oven inside the coffin and many families
choose to also burn other elements
such as flowers some object that has
great sentimental value etc.
the jewelry that they want to burn with the
deceased are confirmed with the
professionals but something that should be
removed first are elements such as the
pacemaker since subjected to high
temperatures they can
explode during the process a large
part of the body such as organs and
other soft tissues are vaporized
due to the heat and the gases are
discharged into the exhaust system the
complete process can last from 2s to 4
hours depending on the size of the
deceased something important is that
the remains are allowed to cool inside the
same
oven once the cooling is finished it is
refined and a part is discarded like
the ashes of the coffin itself
funeral directors usually distinguish them well by
the type of density however at this
point in the process
some bones are still found without being undone
these remains are taken  to another
different machine called a cremator which is a
special processor that crushes the
fragments as for the skull, several
sources assure that it usually retains its
shape and density during incineration
and since its dimensions do not pass through
the hole of the cremator it is common that
during the cremation process it must
be hit with very
long tools similar to a rake to
reduce its size and make it
possible to turn it into ashes this
practice has created many
controversies approximately one or two days
later the
ashes are delivered to the relatives in urns or another
type of case or reliquary today
there are many possibilities such as
inserting ashes in pendants there are
people who are afraid of being
given the ashes of another person
however in countries like Spain the law
requires that each oven have the
capacity for only one body at a time
since burning several bodies
simultaneously is an illegal practice in
addition a cremation certificate must be delivered
certifying the identity
of the remains the only exception to
incineration of more than one body would be
that of a pregnant mother and her
child something that has surprised us is
that  the moment of cremation the
deceased can make certain
movements of hands fingers or knees
has seemed very disturbing to us
But this also has an explanation
tic tackers does not mean that that
person is waking up by
General rule the bodies are left in
cold chambers Until the time of
incineration arrives and the sudden change
in temperature from cold to extreme heat
can generate some
movement something very important about the
work of funeral directors is that
unlike what many think they
are exposed to great
physical and mental dangers let's not forget that not
all deaths are due to
natural causes many people die from
viruses and these people must maintain
safety protocols to fulfill
their duties Without endangering their
lives we just have to remember not long ago
the years of the covid pandemic these
professionals accumulated dozens of
deaths in the funeral homes having to take
extreme caution not to
get infected other great
dangers are the mental consequences And
although not everyone is worth it in this profession
And these professionals
are used to seeing
deceased people every day, no one prepares them
to collect scattered remains for
example When someone  throws himself out of a
floor window and no part of the
body remains intact or when they have to
prepare the body of a
small child who had so much left to live or in the moments when they are given bodies in an advanced state of putrefaction because they have had to go through other previous processes with forensics And it is that although the forensics are in charge of determining the cause of death in people who have not died of
natural causes in many occasions
After several judicial procedures
these bodies are sent to the funeral homes
to prepare and proceed with the
funeral ritual according to testimonies that we have
found sometimes the skin
is so rotten that the simple act of
grabbing an eyelid can mean that
all that skin remains stuck to your fingers
like chewing
gum other examples are the bodies of
some donors there are people who
donate their entire body but others only a
part of it and the family decides to bury what is
left of it in many cases these
bodies can be inconsistent if
the muscles and bones are donated imagine
what that task is like if you have to prepare a body in which when you lift the leg it can break due to lack of support in  a very interesting podcast
from Channel 17 gr they invited a
mortician who stated that
sometimes they had to fill these types of
bodies with cardboard to add firmness
have you ever imagined something like
this in addition to all this although not all
funeral directors have these functions
many of them must assist
families surround you Diary of the pain and
sadness of the people is something that little by
little affects your mood and you must
be very strong mentally so
that it does not affect your personal life
from here we send our deepest
to the professionals of the funeral sector
for the enormous but very necessary work
that they carry out surely the
procedures that we have described
vary from one funeral home to another and
especially depending on the country and
culture always comment respectfully if you
have information that any of these
actions are carried out differently
And so we will all learn We want to know
your
opinion Do not forget to subscribe and give a
Like if you liked it And you can also
follow us on our social networks
Facebook Twitter and Instagram until the
next video